告诉你个有趣的事实
Here's a fun Postal fact.
我们的信箱
Yeah, the inner side of our mailbox
其实是受到联邦政府的管辖的
is under federal jurisdiction.
所以如果你打断我的右手大拇指
So, if you broke my right thumb,
警察会来抓你
that's Pasadena city police.
如果你打断我的左手大拇指
But if you broke my left thumb,
你就要被联邦调查局追查了
that's the FBI.
要是我打断他的手指就得坐牢 我宁愿杀了他呢
If I'm going to jail, I'm killing him, not breaking his thumb.
是啊
No.
哦 我奶奶给我写信了
Oh, I got a letter from my Meemaw.
嗯 你闻闻
Umm. Smell this.
这是什么味道?
What is that?
玫瑰 万通筋骨贴 还有擦脚的足粉
Uh, roses, bengay, and Dr. Schools' foot powder.
"奶奶" CK最新香水
Yeah, "Grandma", by Calvin Klein.
我收到的最后一封手写的信
Yeah, the last time I got a hand written letter,
上面说我停车跟瞎了一样
it was from someone who told me I parked like a blind person.
我知道是谁给你写的
That someone has a name.
呃 谢谢
Uh, thank you.
哦 奶奶买了一副新的假牙
Oh, Meemaw got a new set of teeth.
哦 她找到她原来的那副了
Oh, but then she found her old ones.
哦 所以现在她只在去教堂的时候戴她的新假牙
Oh, so now the new ones are just gonna be her church teeth.
真有趣 就好像你有两副斯波克的耳朵
Fun. Like your Comic-Con Spock ears
一副去漫展戴 一副在家里戴
and your around the house Spock ears.
我停车没问题啊
I park fine.
天啊 她要来看我!
Oh, my goodness, she's coming to visit!
哦 能和她见面肯定很棒
Oh, it'll be nice to finally meet her.
你会爱死她的
Oh, you are going to love her.
她是全世界最和蔼 最可爱的女人
She is the kindest, sweetest woman you'll ever meet.
除非你是一只地鼠 在她的菜园子里钻来钻去
Yeah, unless you're a gopher digging up her vegetable garden.
如果你是的话
In that case, you can expect
她就会用铲子砸碎你的脑袋
to have your head bashed in with a shovel.
* 宇宙一度又烫又稠密 *
* Our whole universe was in a hot, dense state *
* 140亿年前终于爆了炸... 等着瞧! *
* Then nearly 14 billion years ago expansion started... Wait! *
* 地球开始降温 *
* The Earth began to cool *
* 自养生物来起哄 穴居人发明工具 *
* The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools *
* 我们建长城 我们建金字塔 *
* We built the Wall We built the pyramids *
* 数学 自然科学 历史 揭开神秘 *
* Math, Science, History, unraveling the mystery *
* 一切由大爆炸开始 *
* That all started with a big bang *
生活大爆炸 第九季第14集
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调:负能量酥酥
校对: 正能量UU
翻译：小黄不小黄 暹罗猫 李小宝Licht
翻译：無限月讀 放假的AU薇
不是她 不是她
That's not her. That's not her.
不是她
That's not her.
不是她 不是她
That's not her. That's not her.
- 不是她  - 真的?
- That's not her.  - Really?
这个老亚洲男人不是你奶奶?
The old Asian man is not your Meemaw?
你这样一点忙都帮不上
And that's not helpful.
我... 我圣诞节送了她一个iPhone
You know, I... I got her an iPhone for Christmas.
我来看看她在哪里
I'll see where she is.
真不错
Oh, that's nice.
她这个年纪大多数人都不喜欢高科技的东西
Most people her age don't embrace technology.
哦 她都不知道她有一个iPhone
Oh, no, she doesn't even know she has it.
我让我妹妹把它放到她包里去的
No, I had my sister slip it in her bag
这样我们就可以用手机定位她了
so that I can track her like a sea turtle.
和你在动物园走丢的时候一样
Same as when we lost you at the zoo.
都说了一百次了
Uh, for the hundredth time,
我闻到爆米花的味道 但是找不到卖爆米花的车子
I smelled kettle corn and couldn't find the cart.
可是这也没法解释
Still doesn't explain
你为什么会跑到高速公路上去
how you ended up on the freeway divider.
我的小月饼!
Moon Pie!
奶奶!
Meemaw!
见到你我好高兴啊!
I'm so happy to see you!
我也好高兴啊!
I'm happy to see you, too!
哦
Oh.
你越来越小了
You got even smaller.
太棒了!
I love it!
呃 奶奶 这位是Leonard
Uh, Meemaw, this is Leonard.
Leonard 这是我奶奶
Leonard, this is my Meemaw.
你好 见到你很高兴
Hi. So nice to finally meet you.
奶奶 我帮你提吧
Let me take this for you, Meemaw.
谢谢
Thank you.
不行不行 你得叫她名字Constance
No. Oh, no. Now you call her "Constance."
我才能叫她奶奶
I call her "Meemaw."
你有自己的奶奶
You have your own Meemaw.
你奶奶在你四岁的时候就死了可和我没关系
It's not my fault she died when you were four.
这样对你的朋友说话真的好吗?
Is that nice to say to your friend?
不好 奶奶
It isn't, Meemaw.
Leonard 对不起
Sorry, Leonard.
你能一直和我们住吗?
Can you please live with us forever?
哦
Oh.
这太可笑了!
That's ridiculous! If you had
如果你有超能力 你一辈子都听别人的话
a superpower, and spent your whole life
隐藏自己的能力
being told to suppress it,
当你终于决定接受自己超能力的时候
when you finally decide to embrace that power,
为什么要一个人躲起来?!
why hide in isolation?!
对不起
I'm sorry,
那你写的冰雪奇缘拿了多少票房啊?!
and how much money did your version of Frozen make?!
我就是随便说说
I'm just saying,
她不该唱什么"让它去吧" 她应该唱
instead of "Let it Go," she should really sing,
"快来看我啊 我躲在冰箱里"
"Look At Me Hiding in a Freezer Like a Dove Bar."
她用冰建造了一个城堡 造了一个雪人
She built an ice castle, made a snow monster
一天之内就让自己变了样
and gave herself a complete makeover in one day.
看看你今天干了什么?
You know what I saw you do today?
你直接从包装里啃了一块奶酪奶油
Eat a block of cream cheese straight from the foil
还瞒着你妻子!
and lie about it to your wife!
不好意思 我听到了你们说的话 你知道吗
Sorry for eavesdropping, but did you know
他们在编出这个故事之前
they actually had the song "Let It Go" in place
就已经有"随它吧"这首歌了?
before they finalized the story?
是啊 说得对 实际上这首歌太受欢迎了
Yeah, that's true. In fact, they liked the song so much,
以至于他们为它重新编了个故事
they retooled the whole script around it.
所以那部电影才烂的要死
Which is probably why that movie sucks.
咱们讨论的是"冰雪奇缘"
Here we are talking about Frozen,
而你 怒火中烧了吧
and yet, you got burned.
小姐 抱歉
Miss, I'm so sorry.
你怎么能够不喜欢那部电影呢?
How can you not like that movie?
我觉得这部电影过誉了
I just think it gets more credit than it deserves.
我一小时前就这么说过
Oh, that's what I said an hour ago.
哇 你俩讨论"冰雪奇缘"都讨论一小时了?
Wow. You've been talking about Frozen for an hour?
你该看看我们讨论恐龙当家的时候
You should've seen us after The Good Dinosaur.
这是一部发生在侏罗纪时代的西部片
It was a classic western set in the post-Jurassic period,
它改变了我的人生
and it changed my life.
环境舒适吗?
Are you comfortable?
非常舒适
Very.
爬完漫长的楼梯
It's nice to rest
还能坐下来歇歇挺不错的
after 800 flights of stairs.
你气喘吁吁的样子真是萌萌哒
You were so cute, huffin' and puffin'.
Amy来了
There's Amy.
你知道你们肯定合得来
I just know you're gonna hit it off.
你俩的时尚感一模一样
You both have the same fashion sense.
哈喽! 快进来 这是我的奶奶
Hello! Come in, say hi to my Meemaw.
嗨 很高兴见到你
Hi. Nice to meet you.
我也很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you, too.
旅途怎么样?
How was your trip?
很棒
Wonderful.
飞行员非常专业
And the pilot did such a good job,
我就奖励了他一颗奶油糖果
I gave him a butterscotch.
太棒了
That's great.
瞧啊 你还坐在Sheldon的专座上呢
And look at you, sitting in Sheldon's spot.
我都没有资格坐在那呢
You know, I don't even get to sit there.
可不
Yeah.
你这辈子都别想了
And you never will.
对了对了 让她表演纸巾那一招
Ooh, hey, oh, ask her to do the tissue thing.
快点 和她说
Do it, ask her.
可以给我一张纸巾吗?
Can I have a tissue?
当然
Of course.
是不是很牛逼?
Isn't that the best?!
她简直就是 "蜘蛛奶"
She's like Grandma Spider-Man.
他很小的时候
He's been saying that
就爱这么说
since he was little.
我到今天都不明白这是啥意思
I still don't know what it means.
好啦 你俩坐下互相了解一下
Oh, well, you two sit down and get to know each other.
我去给你准备房间
I'll get your room ready.
不许翻我的行李箱
Oh, now don't you go looking through
去找你的礼物
my suitcase for presents.
假如我翻了 能找到礼物吗?
If I did, would I find any?
大概吧
Maybe.
但是你也可能会翻到我的胸罩和灯笼裤
But you also might find my brassieres and bloomers.
值得冒险!
That's a risk I'm willing to take!
太好了
Well, this is so nice.
你来了他这么激动 而且...
He's so excited to have you here and...
好了 现在我来把话直说了吧
Okay, now let's you and me get something straight.
他可能以为我过来是给他做曲奇饼的
He may think that I came to bake him cookies,
但是实际上我是来评价你的
but the real reason is to size you up.
评...
S-S...
评价我?
Si-Size me up?
Sheldon的妈妈可能对你很满意
Sheldon's mother may be okay with you,
但我就没那么简单了
but I'm not so easy.
我... 我...
Well, I...I'm...
我想你了解我之后就会喜欢我了吧
I'm sure you'll like me once you get to know me.
你最好是这么想
Oh, you better hope so.
一辆带正宗喇叭铃铛的
A Texas Special cattle and calf car train set
德克萨斯特别小牛火车!
with authentic horn and bell!
谢谢你 奶奶!
Thank you, Meemaw!
不用谢 小月饼
Oh, you're welcome, Moon Pie.
Amy 你怎么
Amy, why don't you
一点都不激动啊?
look excited?
你可以看着我玩这个啦!
Well, you get to watch me play with this!
你在看萨迦啊
Oh, I see you're reading Saga.
我听说还不错
Yeah, I hear it's pretty good.
确实 不是所有漫画封面上都是有
It is, and not a lot of comics have a woman with wings
一个正给孩子喂奶的长翅膀的女人的
breastfeeding a baby right on the cover.
我相信你说的
I'll take your word for it.
你是该信
You should.
他盯着看了可久
He's really looked.
对了 我叫Raj
I'm Raj, by the way.
- 他是Howard  - 嗨
- This is Howard.  - Hi.
我叫Claire
Claire.
我以前没在这见过你啊 Claire
Well, I've seen you here before, Claire.
我第一次来这
It's my first time.
我在为我的电影剧本找灵感
I'm looking for inspiration for this movie I'm writing.
你是编剧?
You're a screenwriter?
编剧 附加酒吧招待
Well, screenwriter, slash bartender,
附加 我已经在我的车里住了一个多月了
slash, a month away from living in my car.
我能懂
Yeah, I get that.
我是科学家
I'm a scientist,
附加派对策划人
slash party planner,
附加狗狗爱好者
slash small-dog enthusiast,
附加...
slash...
说到 "科学家" 的时候就应该闭嘴
guy who probably should have stopped at "scientist."
你真是科学家?
You're really a scientist?
天文学家
Well, astrophysicist.
那太棒了
That's perfect.
你觉得我写电影的时候能找你咨询吗?
Do you think I could pick your brain for my movie some time?
就是给孩子们看的科幻动画
It's animated sci-fi for kids.
－ Sure. I love animated movies.  － He does,
－ 当然了 我超爱动画片  － 他爱得疯狂
他还有星际宝贝全套收藏为证呢
and he has the Lilo & Stitch collector plates to prove it.
我给自己的生活增光添彩碍着你了还真对不起啊
Excuse me for wanting a little magic in my life.
这是我的号码
Here's my number.
给我打电话 我们可以一起聊一聊
Give me a call, we'll get together.
好极了 再会
Yeah, great. See ya.
拜拜
Yeah, bye.
你这是干嘛呢?
What are you doing?
你是有女朋友的人
You have a girlfriend.
－ So?  － So,
－ 所以呢?  － 所以
你觉得她对你给一个美女的
how do you think she'd feel
剧本提供帮助这件事会怎么想?
about you helping a beautiful girl with her screenplay?
我不会用美来形容她
I wouldn't say she's beautiful.
是吗? 你不觉得她很迷人?
Really? You don't think she's attractive?
我当然觉得 但我不会告诉我女朋友
I do. I just wouldn't tell my girlfriend.
constance 你确定不喝点酒吗?
Constance, are you sure I can't pour you some wine?
噢 别给我倒了
Oh, no wine for me.
Sheldon正给我准备我的威士忌呢
Sheldon's bringing me my whiskey.
给你 奶奶 我是完全
Here you go, Meemaw. I made it
按你的喜好做的...
just how you like...
一倒一大杯
a lot in a glass.
你真贴心 小月饼
Thank you, Moon Pie.
我很好奇
Um, curious.
为什么你叫Sheldon小月饼
Why do you call Sheldon "Moon Pie?"
因为他又香又甜
'Cause he's so nummy-nummy.
她简直可以一口把他吃掉
She could just eat him up.
而我叫她奶奶嘛
And I call her "Meemaw""
是因为 你看看就知道了
because, well, just, well, look at her.
说来真有意思啊
It's interesting that
Leonard和Penny都知道他的昵称是怎么来的
Leonard and Penny know about his nickname
但你什么都不知道
and you don't.
你知道吗
Oh, well, you know,
现在一听嘛 确实是挺熟悉的
now... now that I'm hearing it, it does sound familiar.
怎么可能呢?
How could it?
我从没告诉过你 你也懒得问问
I never told you, and you never bothered to ask.
姐现在就是知道了
Well, now I know. Yeah.
Penny 我听说你有了新的工作
So, Penny, I understand you have a new job.
是的
Yes.
我是一个药物销售代表
I'm a pharmaceutical sales rep.
噢
Oh.
你们都市女生能两全其美真是太好了
It's so wonderful that you modern gals can have it all.
一个丈夫和一份全职工作
A husband and a full-time career.
我也有全职工作和一段稳定的恋情
I have a relationship and a full-time career, too.
这可不是什么好兆头
That doesn't bode well.
为什么? 你刚刚也说了对她而言是行得通的
Why not? You... you just said it's okay for her to work.
Leonard不像Sheldon这么需要被呵护
Well, Leonard doesn't need as much tending to as Sheldon does.
而且按小月饼的话来说
And as Moon Pie explained,
Leonard的工作
Leonard's work
更像是一个业余爱好
is more of a hobby.
那就是我的好朋友
That's my best friend.
是啊
Yeah.
听着
Look,
我明白你很保护你的孙子
I... I get that you're protective of your grandson,
但他现在已经成年了
but he's an adult now.
或许我比你更能明白他的需要
Maybe I understand what he needs better than you do.
我对你的真诚表示感激 亲爱的
I appreciate your honesty, dear.
－ Thank you.  － And here's
－ 谢谢  － 我也
有些大实话要告诉你
some more honesty:
我实在不怎么喜欢你
I don't like you very much.
既然这样 我大概也不怎么喜欢你
Well, maybe I don't like you either.
别 别 别 别 别啊
No, no, no, no, no,
别这样啊 你们必须得相互喜欢啊
no, no, no. Y... You have to like each other.
我们还在苹果小蜜蜂预订了4:30的位子呢
Well, we have a 4:30 reservation at Applebee's.
我想我该走了
I think I should leave.
为什么呢?
But why?
除了你们俩吵架以外
Other than you two fighting,
我们一起多开心啊
we're having such a good time.
你离开这个屋子下一秒 你亲爱的奶奶大人
The minute you left the room, your precious meemaw
就会让我的日子非常难过了
started giving me a really hard time.
我用不着受这份罪
I don't need this.
让她走吧
Let her go.
任何情况下
And under no circumstance
你都不要把那枚订婚戒指给她
will you give her that engagement ring.
什么戒指?
What ring?
我们还是给他们点私人空间吧
Maybe we should give them some privacy.
行行行
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
你先走 我马上就来
You go ahead. I'll catch up with you.
你准备了订婚戒指?
You have an engagement ring?
对
Yes.
Penny 你知道这事儿吗?
Penny, did you know about this?
行了 我们走
All right, let's go.
你什么时候准备的订婚戒指?
When did you get an engagement ring?
我妈妈给我的
My mother gave it to me,
本来我是打算把它给你的
and I had been thinking about giving it to you,
但那时我们分手了
but then we broke up.
呵呵 还真是谢天谢地啊
Well, thank goodness for that.
Sheldon 能不能麻烦你让你奶奶
Sheldon, will you please tell your grandmother
别来瞎掺和?
to stay out of this?
我恐怕做不到
Oh, I don't think I could do that.
Sheldon 告诉这丫头
Sheldon, tell this girl
我的戒指永远都不可能出现在她手上
that my ring will never be on her finger.
你...
Y...
那个本王也做不到啊
I'm gonna opt out of that one, too.
谁说我愿意跟他订婚来着？
Who said I even want to be engaged to him?
而且就算我愿意 我也不想要你传下来的东西!
And if I do, I...I don't need your hand-me-downs!
好了 好了!
All right, all right!
我们都...
Look, l-let's all...
我们都保持冷静
let's remain calm
具体分析一下
and analyze this situation.
我意识到你们才
Now, I realize that you've only known each other
互相认识了不到一天
for less than a day,
但是有可能这场争执是因为
but is it possible this crankiness is because
你们的生理期同步了吗?
your cycles have synced?
你还是出去吧
You leave the room
大人说话小孩别插嘴
and let the grown-ups talk.
马上就出去
Now.
别像对小孩一样的跟他说话
Don't speak to him like he's a child.
谢谢 我还是去隔壁跟Leonard玩吧
Thank you. I'm gonna go next door and play with Leonard.
你遇见了这个女孩 你们交换了电话号码
Okay, so you met this girl, you exchanged numbers,
而且你还打算再见她
and you're gonna meet up with her.
只是帮她写剧本而已
Just to help her with her screenplay.
好吧 我想那也不算太糟
Oh. Well, I guess that's not so bad.
你又不在那儿
You weren't there.
他根本是在勾搭人家
He was really flirting.
美国女孩喜欢幻想
Hey, it's not my fault if American women project
带魔幻口音能实现愿望的异域人士
their fantasies on foreigners
又不是我的错
with the kind of magical voice that grants wishes.
我相信没事的
I'm sure it was harmless.
勾勾搭搭而已 没什么大不了
People flirt. No big deal.
真的吗? 如果我也...
Really? So it's okay if I fl...
你不行 你是本宫的人
Not you. I own your ass.
真正的问题是 你和Emily到哪一步了?
The real question is, where are you with Emily?
不好说啊
Uh, it's hard to say.
我觉得我们还好 可这样的事情
I think we're good, but things like this
总让我犹豫Emily是不是我的真命
make me wonder if Emily's really the right person for me.
我是说 你们有没有对彼此犹豫过?
I mean, did you guys ever have doubts about each other?
- 从来没有啊  - 肯定犹豫过
- No. Never.  - Absolutely.
什么?
What?
Howie 你忘了
Howie, you forget
我们刚开始约会时
how much of our early dates
你不停表演魔术
involved you doing magic
而我总是像这样
and me doing this.
好吧
Fine.
我对你也是有保留的
I had reservations about you, too.
你没有
No, you didn't.
是啊 我没有
No, I didn't.
反正现在也无所谓了
Well, it doesn't matter now,
只要结局让我满意就行
'cause I love how things worked out.
我也是
Me, too.
我觉得你比这支玫瑰花
And I think you're even more beautiful
漂亮多了
than this rose.
最后一次看见我奶奶时
Wow. The last time I saw my grandma,
最有意思的事情是瞅着
the most exciting thing was watching the ash
她香烟的烟灰越来越长还不断好奇
of her cigarette get longer and wondering
烟灰会不会掉进她的布丁里
if it was gonna fall in her pudding.
掉进去了吗?
Did it?
正好掉进去
Yeah, right in there.
她还整个都吃了
She ate it and everything.
Leonard和Penny开门
Leonard and Penny.
Leonard和Penny开门 Leonard和Penny开门
Leonard and Penny. Leonard and Penny.
进来!
Come in!
怎么样了?
Hey. What happened?
Amy走了?
Is Amy gone?
没有 她们让我走开
No. They asked me to leave
以便单独沟通
so they could speak privately.
是啊 气氛蛮紧张的
Uh-oh. Yeah, I know. It was quite tense.
下面是最关键的问题:
So here's the million dollar question:
谁打算冲进去把我的火车拿出来?
uh, who wants to pop over there and get my trains?
好吧 我决定了
All right. I've made up my mind.
我要做正确的事情 给这个女孩打电话
I'm gonna do the right thing, call this girl,
告诉她我已经有人了
and let her know that I'm in a relationship.
目前我们已经听到的有
Okay, so far we've heard,
下定决心 甩了Emily
"made up my mind, I'm dumping Emily."
下定决心 假扮孪生兄弟
"Made up my mind to date both of them
脚踏两条船
by pretending to be twin brothers."
还有 下定决心
And "made up my mind,
提议同床御二女
"I'll ask for a threesome
如果他们拒绝的话 就当成玩笑好了
and if they say no, play it off as a joke."
我在打电话了
I'm calling her.
而且御二女什么的也不至于让你笑破肚皮
And the threesome didn't deserve the belly laugh it got.
是啊
You're right.
还是完全有可能的嘛
It could totally happen.
喂?
Hello?
我是Raj
Hi. Hi. Yeah, it's Raj.
Rajesh 我们在漫画书店见过
Rajesh. We met at the comic book store.
怎么样? 你什么时候有空吗?
Hey, what's up? Figure out what time you're free?
这正是我打电话的原因
Actually, that's why I'm calling.
我...呃...
I, um... I just...
我得告诉你我已经有女朋友了
I need to let you know that I have a girlfriend.
呵呵 行啊
Okay. Good for you.
不是 不是
Well, no, no.
我不想在你约我出去后
I-I didn't want to mislead you
让你误会
after you asked me out.
我没约你出去啊
I didn't ask you out.
你只要你帮我写剧本
I just need help with my screenplay.
你是说我们没来电吗?
Wait, are you saying that we didn't have a vibe?
我们有没有来电有什么关系? 你有女朋友了啊
Why do you care if we have a vibe? You have a girlfriend.
行了! 我只是告诉你我有女朋友了
Come on! I just told you I had a girlfriend.
你也至少可以告诉我我们来电
The least you can do is tell me if we had a vibe.
行吧 我们之间来电
Sure, we had a vibe.
我就知道 我们确实很来电
I knew it. Okay, we did have a vibe.
太激动人心了
This is exciting.
下一步我该怎么做？
What's my next move?
你依然是个有女朋友的人
You still have a girlfriend.
对 接得漂亮
Right. Good catch.
不管怎么样 很抱歉浪费你的时间
Anyway, so I'm sorry to waste your time.
呃... 祝你的剧本写作顺利
And, uh... and good luck with your screenplay.
等等
Hang on.
我们都是成年人了
We're both adults.
可以毫无深意地待在一块儿
We can still get together without it meaning anything.
我不行 自从你说出我们之间很来电那句话之后
Not me. Ever since you admitted we had a vibe,
我已经在脑补我俩的婚礼了
I've been planning our wedding.
只是喝咖啡而已
Look, it's just coffee.
我会问你一些科学问题
I'll ask you some questions about science,
如果你向我求婚的话 我一定会拒绝
and if you propose, I promise to say no.
好 有点伤人 但可以接受
Okay. That hurts a little, but okay.
太好了 回头给你发简讯
Great. I'll text you.
再见
Bye.
好的
All right.
我们要像成年人一样喝杯咖啡
So, uh, we're meeting for coffee like two adults.
皆大欢喜 简单得很
Everybody's happy. Easy peasy.
你打算告诉Emily吗？
Are you gonna tell Emily?
当然
Yeah, of course.
我们之间没有秘密
We have no secrets.
你打算什么时候告诉她？
When are you gonna tell Emily?
奶油芝士的事他说谎了！
He lied about the cream cheese!
他把整块都吃掉了! 我亲眼看到了！
He ate the whole thing! I saw him!
我知道你觉得我不适合Sheldon
Look, I know you think I'm not right for Sheldon,
但是信我吧 他也没多少选择了
but trust me, I'm his best shot.
你不知道我忍受了多少!
You have no idea how much I put up with!
我比你想象得知道的更多
I know more than you think I do.
真的吗? 你知道约会之夜被
Really? You know what it's like to have date night ruined
Google改变字体这件事毁掉是什么感觉吗?
小妞啊
Young lady,
如果你认为我不明白
if you think I don't know
和一个固执又自负的人生活在一起
what it's like to live
是什么感觉
with a stubborn, egotistical man,
那你就大错特错了
then you're wrong.
因为我的丈夫就是那样的
'Cause that was my husband.
真的吗?
Really?
有那么些日子我都想在他的口袋里装满玉米粒
There were days I wanted to fill his pockets with corn
再把他丢到啄人的鸽群里去
and toss him in the pigpen.
如果你明白的话
Well, if you understand,
为什么又要为难我呢？
then why are you giving me such a hard time?
因为你和Sheldon分手的时候
Because when you broke up with Sheldon,
他伤得很重
it hurt him deeply,
我不希望再看到这样的事情发生
and I don't want to see that happen again.
嗨 不好意思
Hi. Sorry.
Sheldon有话要跟您说
Sheldon would like to say something to you.
我没话可说
No, I wouldn't.
进来嘛
Just get in here.
你们好
Hello.
去吧
Go ahead.
奶奶
Meemaw, look,
很抱歉...
I'm sorry, but...
但是我得为
I have to defend
我的女朋友辩护
my girlfriend to you.
Sheldon 谢谢
Oh, Sheldon, thank you.
棒呆 你又要多愁善感了是不是
Oh, great, now you're gonna get emotional.
我一直很尊敬您和爷爷
I always looked up to you and Pop-Pop.
我… 我知道他是一个多么难搞的人
I... I know what a challenging man he could be,
但是我看到你一直陪在他身边 让他
but I saw you stand by him and-and make him
成为了一个更好的人
into a better person.
确实如此
I did.
这也完全是
Yeah, well, that is exactly
过去五年里我和这个小半成品
what I've been doing the last five years
一直在经历的事
with this little work in progress.
他从未让人失望 是不?
He never disappoints, does he?
我想Sheldon是想说
I think what Sheldon means to say is
我们俩一起成长了
we've both grown together.
对吗?
Isn't that right?
嗯...
Well...
快说是
Say yes.
是
Yes.
好吧
Fine.
如果你感受如此强烈 我也不会妨碍你们的好事
If you feel so strongly, I won't stand in your way.
太感谢了
Thank you.
所以如果他想
So if he wanted
把那个订婚戒指给我的话
to give me that engagement ring,
也能得到您的同意咯？
we would have your blessing?
我想是的
I suppose.
女人 我才刚刚把我的童贞给你
I just gave you my virginity, woman.
冷静点
Cool your jets.
如果你把故事改成
Yeah, see, if you just change the story
我们这个星系毁灭了
to the destruction of our galaxy,
那么一个超级巨型的黑洞就会产生了
then a super massive black hole could work.
很棒
This is great.
太感谢你了
Thank you so much.
我只需想出一种让所有人都死去
I just got to figure out a way for everyone
又不让小孩感到害怕的方式就好了
to die that isn't too scary for children.
这就是粑粑麻麻相识的过程
And that's how Mommy and Daddy met.
嘿 你告诉Emily我俩的事了吗？
Hey, did you ever tell Emily about us?
我会的！
I will!